Ndigithe John Ndirangu

P.O.BOX 812-051000

+254769968711 | ndigithejohn@gmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-ndigithe-8935381ab

@JohnNdigithe

Objective

Results oriented and efficient individual with much knowledge in software development. I possess excellent knowledge in latest frameworks used in software development, whether in testing or developing softwares. I'm a Fullstack engineer proficiency in Frontend Frameworks like React and React Native for mobile applications and Next js for server-side rendering also in Backend framework like Nodejs and also work with Rest APIs using Nodejs rest framework, and manage the state of the application using Redux For deployment purposes I have worked with docker for containing the applications and Nginx web server which works as a reverse proxy to manage requests between the client and backend application

Experience

• The Jitu 2nd May 2023 - 27th July 2023

Attachee

Gained valuable skills in

Fronted development using HTMI and CSS (including Grid, Flexbox), ReactJS,

Proficient in using MSSQL for database management

Developed expertise in backend development using Node.js Express

• **Zuridesk** 1-10-2024 - To date

Software developer Intern

At Zuridesk, I have been developing scalable web applications using React, Node.js, and third-party libraries, optimizing front-end performance, integrating APIs, and managing state with Redux while ensuring clean, maintainable code.

Education

The Dedan Kimathi University of Science and Technology
 Bachelor of Science Computer Science

2019-2024

• Kahuho Uhuru High School

2015-2018

В

Rironi Primary School

2007-2014

320 (B)

RST Forum india
 Full Stack Development bootcamp
 Certificate of completion

27-05-2024 to 9-09-2024

Skills

- Third-Party Integration: M-Pesa Gateway I have expertise in integrating third-party services like the M-Pesa gateway into web
 applications, enabling secure and convenient payment processing and financial transactions for users.
- Agile Development Practices- I embrace Agile development practices, such as Scrum or Kanban, to drive collaborative and iterative development processes.
- Frontend Development: React- I excel in building dynamic and responsive user interfaces using React and third party libraries such as TanStack Query and Redux for state management, Chakra UI and Tailwind CSS for UI, React Hook Form for form validations and React Router for routing.
- Backend Development: With Node.js and Express.js, I build robust and scalable backend solutions for web applications. Express.js,
 a fast and minimalist framework, allows me to efficiently handle routing, middleware, and API development. Additionally, I ensure
 seamless frontend-backend communication by utilizing Redux for state management and data flow.

Personal Details

Marital Status: Single
Nationality: Kenyan
Religion: Christian
GitHub: Ndigithe-john

Language : English and Kiswahili (fluently spoken and written)

Portfolio : https://ndigithe-john.vercel.app

Reference

Dr.Gabriel M. Kamau, PHD - Dedan Kimathi University of Science and Technology
 Chair, Department of Computer Science(COD)
 gabriel.kamau@dkut.ac.ke
 +254720955821

• Francis Gatehi - Zurisedk Software Engineer 0789 653090

• Oreste Keikei - Zuridesk Software Engineer 0719 358359